Hunter Norris III

Summary:

I am a Financial Technology Professional currently working as a Business Analyst in the Home Preservation Mortgage arena with experience in Agile and Waterfall methodologies that has a vast amount of financial experience and industry knowledge. I am interested in advancing my life by pursuing personal and career goals while being an asset to the organization.

Professional Experience:

Wells Fargo - Simplified Home Preservation Pre-Decision Scrum Team

Business Analyst

Charlotte NC August 2019-Present

- Research business request for technology development to quantify the need to deliver the technology change in a future development release
- Analyze existing risk factors and the benefit of delivering technology changes to reduce risk.
- Research dependencies and seek clarification from business and technical partners on development request
- Act as a liaison between business and development partners when addressing production defects
- Provide demos of existing defects for development team members
- Provide demos of newly developed user stories that will be deployed to the production environment
- Update task and user story related items in Jira
- Review and export reports and other metrics from Jira to analyze team performance
- Assist the Product Owner in drafting user stories and technical documentation in Jira
- Extract production release data from Jira for the PM to solicit for production release approval
- Organize and facilitate meetings with other teams, internal resources and vendors in efforts to clear impediments
- Assist in providing priority with Backlog Refinement
- Complete rule based configuration and unit testing to satisfy user stories
- Actively participate in scrum team Retrospectives to identify and document what went well, what could have gone better within a recently completed sprint and action items for future sprint work
- Actively participate in Pre-Planning and Big Room Planning activities with all other scrum teams to plan and forecast future scrum team work initiatives.

Wells Fargo - Delivery Management, Customer Contact and Default Decisioning

Business Liaison Consultant 2, DXC-Early Resolution Vendor Management Charlotte NC 2014-2019

- Conduct meetings with business partners to prioritize vendor code defects fixes and enhancements to the Early Resolution Application
- Engage in discussion with vendors on new technology and to determine if it can add value to Home Mortgage default operations groups and technology partners

- Analyze code delivered from vendors and relay details to lines of business for the code to be implemented in conjunction with internal technology changes to be delivered in Speed to Market releases or traditional enterprise releases in compliance with SDLC.
- Extract historical vendor code ticket data from internal databases to assist business partners researching issues.
- Create toolkits containing details from third party vendor release notes containing Day One
 visual changes and Key Enhancements drafted in a format that operations business partners can
 understand
- Provide traceability metrics around the lifecycle of vendor code tickets
- Complete intake analysis and change management workbooks for vendor products to determine risk, technology, organization, and financial impacts.
- Create and present a weekly Power Point presentation displaying updates from the vendor, milestones, and the status of vendor code testing.
- Reconcile defects provided by the vendor against defects that are recorded in ALM.
- Work with Supply Chain partners to provide items to be included in SLA and contract negotiations with third party vendors.
- Review changes with the mortgage system of record vendor and determine if the impact of a change to their tool will directly or indirectly impact other tools, policies and procedures that read or write to the system of record.
- Provide detailed business cases to senior management once value has been assessed for new vendor based technology changes.
- Host weekly meetings with technology vendors discussing policy changes and new products such as government sponsored modifications and how it impact will impact existing tools
- Ensure that vendor changes are in compliance with contractual terms, SLA's, internal rules and regulations and are in compliance with the Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC) as well as Third Party Service Provider Policies and Procedures (TPSP)

Wells Fargo - Technology Operations Group

Application System Engineer 4 Early Resolution Configuration Team Lead

Charlotte NC 2011-2014

- Supervised daily operations of the Early Resolution Configuration Development Team
- Provide business rule based configuration guidance and design perspectives to the Early Resolution development team.
- Review, approve/reject Business Requirements Definition, Functional System Design, and Change Request Documents for the implementation of configuration changes to the Early Resolution Application.
- Queried loans with specific criteria to assist in testing and researching defects.
- Assign production defects and defects found in QA testing to members of the Early Resolution Development Team for resolution.
- Adhere to policies and procedures governed by the Software Development Lifecycle and ensure that configuration processes are in compliance.
- Discuss and participate in the implementation of future enhancements with vendor, DXC that would add benefit to the Early Resolution Application
- Participate in vendor code deployments to the UAT and Production environments to ensure that the code is working as expected.
- Work closely with the Early Resolution vendor to maintain, negotiate, review and approve the
 deployment of code changes to the application. Manage the applications configuration team
 development and testing of vendor based code enhancements.
- Complete Installment, Validation, and Recovery documentation for production releases for configuration and code deployment.

• Provide demonstrations of configuration changes within the Early Resolution Application to respective business units displaying and discussing configuration changes.

Skills:

- Tech savvy
- 20+ years of mortgage default technology implementation experience
- Advanced knowledge of Wells Fargo default mortgage tools and system of record such as: Early Resolution, MSP, ALM, PAC2000, Jira, Blueprint
- Experienced with HP Quality Center
- Proficient in writing and executing SQL queries
- Proficient in writing requirements and functional system designs
- Business rule based configuration
- Strong proficiency with Microsoft Office Suite
- Superior Communication and collaboration skills
- Superior team and management leadership skills
- Knowledge of the IT industry, vendors, and best practices
- Superior mortgage and financial knowledge

Education:

- Financial Technology Certification Program completed 3/10/2021
- 2 years completed at Morgan State University 1997-1999
- High School Diploma Milford Mill High Academy 1996